Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection 1890-1970 AD.MC.002
AbuDhabi
The Yasser Alwan Collection
Bulk, 1890-1960
1890-1970
AD.MC.002
AbuDhabi
7.0 Paige boxes
Box 1-7
Biographical/Historical note
Yasser Alwan is an independent photographer based in Cairo. His photographs have been exhibited in Cairo, New York, Frankfurt, San Francisco, London, Canterbury and Abu Dhabi. New York University Abu Dhabi hosted a retrospective of his work during the 2011-12 academic year. He is currently teaching photography at the German University in Cairo.
Scope and Contents note
The Yasser Alwan collection includes more than 2000 personal, family and studio photographs and offers a varied and often surprising view of the ethnic, cultural and social diversity that characterized Egyptian society in the first half of the twentieth century.
Photographer Yasser Alwan started visiting various flea markets and book merchants in Cairo in the mid-1990s, purchasing old prints and negatives. Most of these date back to the 1920s, 1930s and 1940s, though there are also a significant number from earlier years. The majority of the photographs were sold individually, but there are also groups of photographs discarded together and a small number of albums.
This fascinating collection of vernacular photography presents a great variety of images depicting daily life in Egypt from the decades before the revolution of 1952, from formal studio portraits to amateur family photos of Egyptians, as well as other Arabs, Turks, Armenians, Greeks, Italians and Western expats who lived in or visited Egypt. There are also photographs of trips abroad taken by Egyptians, as well as a collection of postcards dating from the early 20th century through to the 1960s.
Arrangement note
The collection has been processed as it was received.
Conditions Governing Access note
Digitization of this collection is underway; thumbnail images will be published here as they become available.
Custodial History note
Akkasah, the Center for Photography at NYU Abu Dhabi, acquired the collection in August 2014.
Egypt; Family Portraits; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Sudan; The Yasser Alwan Collection; Wedding Portraits
- Series I: Sudan - Gordon Studio, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan) (Box 1)
  Sudan; The Yasser Alwan Collection
  - Officials walking outside a building with flags, following two soldiers in ceremonial dress. 11.4 x 7.0 cm, 1922-1953; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Events / Occasions; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Insignia / Emblem; Khartoum, Sudan; Military / Soldiers; Officials; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - Two African tribesmen in traditional dress. 7.2 x 11.4 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewellery; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Traditional Dress
  - Sudanese military officials in three rows. 14.6 x 8.6 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Buildings; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Military / Soldiers; Navy; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Uniforms
  - A group portrait of men wearing military uniforms standing in front of an area decorated with crests and streamers. 9.9 x 7.5 cm, 1922-1953; Grey, Abby Weed, 1902-1978; Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Events / Occasions; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Insignia / Emblem; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Swords & Knives; Uniforms
  - Two men outdoors, one sitting at an easel and drawing, the other standing and looking into the camera. 11.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Carriages & Coaches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Handkerchief; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Suits
  - The Saudi Arabian army at Mount Arafat in Mecca. Wide angle photo showing a huge crowd with camels. 8.9 x 6.0 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Arrangement note
    with Arabic writing in the back
    Arabic Writing; Camels; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mecca, Saudi Arabia; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Pilgrims; Studio Photography; Tents
  - A Sudanese soldier with facial markings in uniform, standing in front of an archway. 7.3 x 11.9 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Turban; Uniforms
  - Sudanese woodwind and brass band, playing on a field. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Brass Instruments; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Music; Musical Instruments; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Uniforms; Woodwind Instruments
  - A Sudanese soldier with facial markings with a camel and a gun. 6.7 x 10.8 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Buildings; Camels; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Individual Portraits; Khartoum, Sudan; Military / Soldiers; Studio Photography; Uniforms
  - A youth wearing traditional dress, carrying two woven baskets on his head. 8.6 x 11.8 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Traditional Dress
  - A group of naked children and women sitting around a tree. 11.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Boys; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Jewellery; Naked; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Traditional Dress; Women
  - A procession of the Sudanese cavalry on camels with guns in front of a British officer. 11.8 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Camels; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Horses; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Uniforms
  - Sudanese men with swords on horseback. 11.6 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Horses; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Swords & Knives; Traditional Dress; Turban
  - A group of tribesmen with shields and spears in a village of thatched houses. 11.1 x 7.1 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Shields; Spears; Studio Photography; Sudan; Traditional Dress
  - A Sudanese soldier with facial markings on a camel. 7.1 x 11.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Camels; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Turban; Uniforms
  - Sudanese soldiers standing at attention with rifles, a troop in the background hold drums. 11.6 x 6.9 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Guns; Military / Soldiers; Musical Instruments; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Uniforms
  - A Sudanese man with three camels in the desert. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Camels; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Individual Portraits; Khartoum, Sudan; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - A steamship on the Nile, with a tug boat named 'panther' beside it. 11.8 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Boats; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Nile River; Photographic Prints; Ships; Studio Photography
  - The Alexandria Corniche and Saad Zaghloul Square. 11.4 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Architecture; Buildings; Carriages & Coaches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Seas; Studio Photography
  - The Dome, "Al Gubba", Kitchener Medical School (now the medical faculty of the University of Khartoum). 11.4 x 7.0 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Architecture; Buildings; Cars; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Medicine; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; University
  - Two tribal men, with clay in their hair, made into a horn. 11.8 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewellery; Men; Photographic Prints; Spears; Studio Photography; Sudan; Swords & Knives; Traditional Dress
  - An official in a dark uniform with a medal, standing with soldiers with swords and guns (duplicates). 10.0 x 8.2 cm and 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Horses; Medals; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Swords & Knives; Uniforms
  - A group of Sudanese men, women and children in traditional dress. 11.2 x 6.5 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    with Arabic writing at the back
    Arabic Writing; Children; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Hats; Head Covers; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Tents; Traditional Dress; Women
  - Two tribal men with spears and helmets. 8.9 x 11.7 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Spears; Studio Photography; Sudan; Traditional Dress
  - Pilgrims gathered around the Kaaba in Mecca, Saudi Arabia. 11.0 x 6.7 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Arabic Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mecca, Saudi Arabia; Photographic Prints; Pilgrims; Studio Photography
  - Sudanese soldiers in uniform standing at attention with bayonets. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Uniforms
  - A military presentation for a British and Sudanese audience, in front of large building (linked ref45). 11.6 x 6.9 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Architecture; Buildings; Ceremonies; Events / Occasions; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Khartoum, Sudan; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Swords & Knives; Uniforms
  - A man in military uniform on horseback with a sword. 11.1 x 8.6 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Horses; Individual Portraits; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Swords & Knives; Uniforms
  - Sudanese traditional houses. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Architecture; Buildings; Electricity; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan
  - A Sudanese man carrying animal skin bag. 9.0 x 14.3 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Traditional Dress
  - Three men grooming a horse, with others looking on. 12.0 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Horses; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan
  - British - Egyptian ceremony, with flags of the Kingdom of Egypt (1923-1958), and the Pyramids of Giza in the background. Old camera in the mid-ground. 11.6 x 7.3 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Archaeological Sites; Cairo, Egypt; Cameras; Ceremonies; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Pyramids of Giza; Studio Photography; Turban
  - An aerial view of a street in Khartoum, Sudan. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Architecture; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Photographic Prints; Streets; Studio Photography
  - The Al Kabir Mosque in Khartoum, Sudan. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Architecture; Buildings; Carriages & Coaches; Donkeys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - A Tabaldi (Baobab) tree outside the walls of a small thatched roof village. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Architecture; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Trees
  - Two mud-brick buildings with domes. 11.2 x 6.8 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A military presentation for a British and Sudanese audience, in front of large building (linked ref35). 11.5 x 6.9 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Architecture; Buildings; Ceremonies; Events / Occasions; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Swords & Knives; Uniforms
  - Planes from 47 Squadron of the RAF in front of the Omdurman Bridge. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, 1926-1939; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Airplanes; Bridges; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Military / Soldiers; Nile River; Photographic Prints; Royal Air Force; Studio Photography; Sudan
  - Planes from 47 Squadron of the RAF and feluccas on the Nile. 10.5 x 6.9 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Airplanes; Boats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Military / Soldiers; Nile River; Photographic Prints; Royal Air Force; Studio Photography; Sudan
  - A roundabout in front of a military compound. 11.9 x 7.1 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Buildings; Cars; Gelatin Silver Prints; Horses; Military / Soldiers; Motorcycles; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan
  - Wadi Wahesh planes and the Towers of the Three Graces in Sudan. 11.1 x 7.1 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains; Oases; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan
  - Four men wearing suits and tarbouches, posing in front of car. 8.3 x 5.9 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Cars; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Mustaches; Studio Photography; Sudan; Suits
  - A traditional felucca sailing boat on the Nile. 6.5 x 9.4 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    with studio logo at the back
    Boats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Nile River; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan
  - A panoramic view of Khartoum. 11.4 x 7.1 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A British military ceremony at the Govenor General's (Presidential) Palace, Khartoum. 11.7 x 7.1 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Architecture; Buildings; Ceremonies; Events / Occasions; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - St Matthew's Cathedral (Khartoum Cathedral) on the banks of the Nile.11.3 x 6.7 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Nile River; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - A car entering the Govenor General's (Presidential) Palace in Khartoum, Sudan. 14.1 x 9.3 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Architecture; Buildings; Cars; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan
  - Four men bulding wooden wheels. 8.9 x 6.1 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Traditional Dress; Turban
  - The Bordein, a paddle steamer built C.1862 by Samuda Brothers of London. 9.1 x 6.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Boats; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Nile River; Steamboats; Studio Photography; Sudan
  - Train carriages transporting quarried stone. 11.4 x 7.0 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Trains
  - A cloudy sky, view from the Omdurman Bridge, Omdurman/Khartoum, Sudan. 11.5 x 7.1 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Architecture; Bridges; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Landscapes; Nile River; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - Felucca sail boats on a tributary of the Nile. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Boats; Countryside / Rural; Gelatin Silver Prints; Nile River; Photographic Prints; Rivers; Studio Photography; Sudan
  - The Gordon Hotel, built 1906. 10.8 x 6.5 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Architecture; Buildings; Dogs; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hotels; Khartoum, Sudan; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - Six men posing with a car on the side of a road. 8.3 x 5.8 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Cars; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Suits; Uniforms
  - A tram crossing the Omdurman Bridge, with boats in the foreground. 11.3 x 6.9 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Architecture; Boats; Bridges; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Nile River; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Tram
  - Al Kabir Mosque - Omdurman's biggest mosque on a cloudy day. 11.4 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Architecture; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan
  - Gordon Studio Business card, A. Kazandjian, Khartoum, Sudan. 13.1 x 8.1 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    with a note at the back
    Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Photographic Prints; Postcards; Studio Photography
  - An aerial view of Khartoum, Sudan. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Architecture; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - Seven men posing with a car and dog (duplicates). 7.9 x 9.9 cm and 11.0 x 7.9 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Cars; Dogs; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Suits
  - A procession of gun mounted military cars in the desert. 12.0 x 7.5 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Cars; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Uniforms
  - A troop of soldiers riding camels, one soldier carries a flag. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Camels; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Men; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Sudan; Swords & Knives; Uniforms
  - Panorama of Khartoum, Sudan. 11.7 x 7.2 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Holy Virgin Mary Coptic Orthodox Cathedral in Khartoum. 11.0 x 7.0 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Khartoum, Sudan; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - Sudanese traditional boats on the river. 7.2 x 11.0 cm, Undated; Gordon Studio, Khartoum (Sudan); Kazandjian, A. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Boats; Gelatin Silver Prints; Nile River; Photographic Prints; Ports; Sudan
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971 (Box 1-7)
  Egypt; The Yasser Alwan Collection
  - Two Armenian women with a basket of flowers (linked ref78). 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Moderne, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Family Portraits; Flowers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - Two Armenian women holding a book (linked ref77). 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Moderne, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Books; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - Two Armenian women with a painted moon backdrop. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Studio Covas, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Cairo, Egypt; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - An Armenian family portrait, two girls wear matching dresses and a boy wears a nautical outfit. 13.7 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Moderne, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Children; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Family Portraits; Flowers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Jewellery; Maritime Outfits; Men; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - An Egyptian man wearing a tarbouche and eye glasses. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Egypt; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Ties
  - An Egyptian man wearing a tarbouche and robe, in front of a painted backdrop. 13.2 x 8.3 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Latif, Kafr El Zaiyat, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Egypt; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - A young man wearing a tarbouche and long black coat in front of a painted backdrop. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Latif, Kafr El Zaiyat, Egypt (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Coats; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - Two men wearing tarbouches and suits. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Handkerchief; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A man wearing a suit and tarbouche, with a young boy seated on a table. 13.6 x 8.6 cm, 28 March 1926; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Family Portraits; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Signature; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A man wearing a suit and tarbouche leaning on a pedestal. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Studio Vincent Photo Egyptienne, Rue Abdine No. 6, Caire (Egypt) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Handkerchief; Individual Portraits; Men; Mustaches; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A man wearing a suit and tarbouche. 13.7 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits